Guide to the Peter Newell Family Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Marcus and Helen Newell Gordon Family Papers, 1890-1965; Series V; 0.8; (2 boxes)
  - GORDON, HELEN LOUISE NEWELL BAKER
    - Correspondence
      - Gordon, Marcus Acheson
        - Outgoing, 1930-31 (Box 206, Folder 2652)
        - Correspondence, 1932 (Box 206, Folder 2653)
        - Outgoing, 1933-35 (Box 206, Folder 2654)
        - Outgoing, 1936, 1938 (Box 206, Folder 2655)
      - Gordon, Robert (Stubby) Bruce, 1923 (Box 206, Folder 2656)
      - John, Alice, 1934-56, n.d. (Box 206, Folder 2657)
      - Jones, Edmund Hazen Jones, Sara, 1913, 1915 (Box 206, Folder 2658)
      - Lydecker, Sally McCormick, 1930-33, n.d. (Box 206, Folder 2659)
      - McCormick, Howard McCormick, Josephine Newell, 1910-ca. 1945 (Box 206, Folder 2660)
      - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1942-57 (Box 206, Folder 2661)
      - Nankivel, Agnes C., 1961-66 (Box 206, Folder 2662)
      - Newell, George F. Newell, Louisa D., 1897 (Box 206, Folder 2663)
      - Other correspondents, 1895-1959 (Box 206, Folder 2664)
    - Personal Papers
      - Address books with miscellaneous notes, n.d. (Box 206, Folder 2665)
      - Diary, Reno, NV, 1923 Jul-Aug (Box 206, Folder 2666)
      - Diary and shipboard menu, France, 1932 May-Jul
      - Diploma, 1901
        See: Oversize, Box 240, Folder 3308
      - Obituary for Judge George Bartlett, n.d. (Box 206, Folder 2667)
      - Piano recital programs, 1901, 1904 (Box 206, Folder 2668)
      - Theater program, 1899 (Box 206, Folder 2669)
  - GORDON, MARCUS ACHESON
    - Correspondence
      - Gordon, Cadmus Z. Gordon, Kate A.
        - Correspondence, 1893-1905 (Box 207, Folder 2670)
        - Incoming, 1914-17 (Box 207, Folder 2671)
        - Incoming, 1918 Jan-Apr (Box 207, Folder 2672)
        - Incoming, 1918 May-Dec (Box 207, Folder 2673)
        - Incoming, 1924 (Box 207, Folder 2674)
      - Scott, Nancy McCormick, ca. 1923 (Box 207, Folder 2675)
    - Personal Papers
      - Certificate, Cornell Alembic, n.d. (Box 207, Folder 2676)
      - Chronology of U.S. Army service, n.d. (Box 207, Folder 2677)
      - Clippings, miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 207, Folder 2678)
      - Diplomas, 1904, 1908
        See: Oversize, Box 240, Folders 3309-3310
      - Drawing, 1896 (Box 207, Folder 2679)
      - Ephemera, miscellaneous, 1930-39 (Box 207, Folder 2680)
      - Floor plans of apartment, Hightstown, ca. 1965 (Box 207, Folder 2681)
      - Locks of hair, 1890 (Box 207, Folder 2682)
      - Obituaries for Isaac and Mary Gordon, 1893, 1916 (Box 207, Folder 2683)
      - U.S. War Department, Special Orders announcement and envelope, 1918 (Box 207, Folder 2684)
      - Valentines (6), 1892-1903 (Box 207, Folder 2685)
      - Valentines (5), 1892-1903 (Box 207, Folder 2686)
      - Valentines (4), 1892-1903 (Box 207, Folder 2687)
      - Valentines (8), 1892-1903 (Box 207, Folder 2688)
  - COSGROVE, HELEN [BETTY] LOUISE BAKER
    - Correspondence
      - Baker, Alfred Z., Sr., 1932 (Box 207, Folder 2689)
      - Benon, Mme. C.
        - Letters from, 1932-40 (Box 207, Folder 2690)
        - Letters from, 1951-59 (Box 207, Folder 2691)
        - Letters from, 1960, 1962 (Box 207, Folder 2692)
      - Gordon, Helen Newell Baker, 1923 Dec 10 (Box 207, Folder 2693)
      - McCormick, Howard and Frank Street, painting class announcement, 1937 Jun (Box 207, Folder 2694)
      - McCormick, Peter Newell McCormick, Sally, 1922 (Box 207, Folder 2695)
      - Reid, [?], condolence note, 1970 Mar (Box 207, Folder 2696)
      - Smith, Charles Edward, 1931-33 (Box 207, Folder 2697)
    - Personal Papers
      - Around the World in Happy Days (published account of the Cosgroves' trip around the world), 1969 (Box 207, Folder 2698)
      - Drawings and notes, ca. 1915-36 (Box 207, Folder 2699)
      - Leonia [NJ] High School "The Leonian," vol. 5, no. 3, 1921 Apr (Box 207, Folder 2700)
      - Silhouette made in Havana, Cuba, ca. 1939 (Box 207, Folder 2701)
      - Other ephemera, 1928-67, n.d. (Box 207, Folder 2702)
- Alfred Zantzinger Baker Sr. Papers, 1892-1986; Series VI; 6.8; (6 boxes)
  Series VI files are arranged in six subseries: Correspondence; Personal Papers; Photographs; Sketches, Designs and Writings; Published Works; and Reference Works.
  - CORRESPONDENCE
    - Appleton-Century Company, 1913-40 (Box 208, Folder 2703)
    - Crawford, Earl Stetson, 1915, n.d. (Box 208, Folder 2704)
    - Karig, Walter, 1937-40 (Box 208, Folder 2705)
    - Karig, Walter, n.d. (Box 208, Folder 2706)
    - Newell, Peter, 1901 (Box 208, Folder 2707)
    - Recklinghausen, Max von, 1928 Mar 9 (Box 208, Folder 2708)
    - Employment letters and references, 1915-20 (Box 208, Folder 2709)
    - Publishers, miscellaneous, 1902-07 (Box 208, Folder 2710)
  - PERSONAL PAPERS
    - Change of address notice, ca. 1910 (Box 208, Folder 2711)
    - Christmas cards, 1925, n.d. (Box 208, Folder 2712)
    - Contracts
      - Books, Frederick A. Stokes Co., 1911-12 (Box 208, Folder 2713)
      - "Electro-Chameleon Drug Store Changing of Color Bottle Device", 1914 (Box 208, Folder 2714)
    - Copyright papers
      - "Stand Behind Our Flag and Our President" (print), 1918 (Box 208, Folder 2715)
      - "Sheba," by N. Elson and A. Z. Baker with sheet music, 1927 (Box 208, Folder 2716)
    - Financial papers
      - Baltimore Trust Company notice, 1938 (Box 208, Folder 2717)
      - Bank checks, cancelled, 1912 (Box 208, Folder 2718)
      - Invoice for supplies, Paris, 1906 (Box 208, Folder 2719)
      - Liberty Weekly, Inc., check stubs, n.d. (Box 208, Folder 2720)
      - Medical receipts, 1912-16 (Box 208, Folder 2721)
    - French artists' societies ephemera, 1907 (Box 208, Folder 2722)
    - National Academy of Design exhibition ticket, 1893 (Box 208, Folder 2723)
      See also: exhibition catalogue in Series I, Box 18, Folder 403
    - Passport and Haitian visa, 1895 (Box 208, Folder 2724)
    - Patent papers
      - Kinematograph, 1911 (Box 208, Folder 2725)
      - Pull toy, 1918 (Box 208, Folder 2726)
      - Toy gun, 1932 (Box 208, Folder 2727)
    - Portrait of Alfred Z. Baker by Balfour Ker, pastel on paper, ca. 1925
      See: Oversize, Box 249, Folder 3402
    - Real estate
      - Nutley, NJ, 1909 (Box 208, Folder 2728)
      - Paris, France, 1905-07 (Box 208, Folder 2729)
    - Residency registration, France, 1907 Jan 8 (Box 208, Folder 2730)
    - Voter registration, New Jersey, 1940 (Box 208, Folder 2731)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS
    - Baker, Alfred Z., Sr.
      - Portraits, 1870-89 (Box 208, Folder 2732)
      - Portraits and candids, 1890-1919 (Box 208, Folder 2733)
      - Portraits and candids, 1920-40 (Box 208, Folder 2734)
    - Baker children, ca. 1911 (Box 208, Folder 2735)
    - Unidentified man, by W. Getz, Baltimore, ca. 1890
      See: Oversize, Box 249, Folder 3403
    - Unidentified portraits, possibly family members, ca. 1880 (Box 208, Folder 2736)
  - SKETCHES, DESIGNS AND WRITINGS
    - Eskimo Music: binding design, ca. 1908 (Box 208, Folder 2737)
    - Heigh-Ho Aluminum: book dummy, n.d. (Box 208, Folder 2738)
    - Old Mother Hubbard
      See: Oversize, Box 250 for the following material:
      - Book dummy, ca. 1910
      - Rag doll cloth pages, ca. 1910
      - Rag doll templates, ca. 1910
    - Paleontological Alphabet
      - Book dummy, 1935 (Box 208, Folder 2739)
      - Book dummy, ca. 1935 (Box 208, Folder 2740)
    - Paleontological/Prehistoric Alphabet
      See: Oversize, Boxes 251-252 for the following material:
      - Photostats of drawings, ca. 1935
      - Drawings, pages A-L (11), ca. 1935
      - Drawings, pages M-Z (14), ca. 1935
    - Prehistoric Alphabet
      - Typescript, ca. 1935 (Box 209, Folder 2741)
      - Extra pieces and pages, ca. 1935 (Box 209, Folder 2742)
    - The Talking and Singing Book of Animals and Birds (Box 209, Folder 2743)
    - book dummy
    - Self-portrait, 1906 (Box 209, Folder 2744)
    - Sketches, miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 209, Folder 2745)
      See also: Series I, Box 154, Folder 2002
    - Writings
      - "After Dinner at Baptiste's," manuscript, n.d. (Box 209, Folder 2746)
      - Animal alphabet poems, manuscript and typescript (Box 209, Folder 2747)
      - "Bundleduppy," typescripts, 1935 (Box 209, Folder 2748)
  - PUBLISHED WORKS
    - Illustrations, clipped from publications
      - Identified publications, 1896-1907, n.d. (Box 209, Folder 2749)
      - Unidentified publications, 1900, n.d. (Box 209, Folder 2750)
    - Illustrations and proofs
      - Animal Jokes, by Mary Baker-Baker and A. Crawford, 1899 (Box 209, Folder 2751)
      - The Moving-Picture Glue Book, 1912 (Box 209, Folder 2752)
      - Fish and wildlife cartoons (Box 209, Folder 2753)
      - Fowl cartoons, n.d. (Box 209, Folder 2754)
      - Giraffe cartoons, n.d. (Box 209, Folder 2755)
      - Hippopotamus and elephant cartoons (Box 209, Folder 2756)
      - Insect cartoons, n.d. (Box 209, Folder 2757)
      - Ostrich cartoons, n.d. (Box 209, Folder 2758)
      - Portraits and vignettes (Box 209, Folder 2759)
    - Scrapbooks containing Baker's work
      See: Oversize, Box 249 for the
      - following material:
      - Clippings and tearsheets from periodicals including Puck, Judge, Life, Criterion, Brooklyn Life, Harper's Bazaar, Evening World, St. Nicholas, Scribner's and the book, Animal Jokes, 1899-1900
      - Clippings and tearsheets from periodicals including Bon Vivant, Rire and Pêle-Mêle, 1905-07, n.d.
    - Tearsheets and issues containing Baker illustrations
      - La Jeunesse illustrée, 1907 Oct 13
        See: Oversize, Box 249, Folder 3406
      - Pêle-Mêle, 1906 Oct 7
        See: Oversize, Box 249, Folder 3407
      - Puck, 1903, 1908, n.d.
        See: Oversize, Box 249, Folder 3408
  - REFERENCE WORKS, PERSONAL COLLECTIONS
    - International music, clippings, n.d. (Box 209, Folder 2760)
    - "Les Images Comiques de la Famille," French comic books (2), 1903 Mar
      See: Oversize, Box 249, Folder 3409
    - Japanese Dance, by Clayton Thomas, proof of sheet music, 1903 (Box 209, Folder 2761)
    - Japanese prints (halftones) (6), n.d.
      See: Oversize, Box 249, Folder 3410
    - "South African Native Music", n.d. (Box 209, Folder 2762)
- Howard McCormick Papers, 1890-1941; Series VII; 5.9; (5 boxes) + 2 oil paintings
  McCormick's papers are arranged in six subseries: Correspondence; Personal Papers; Writings and Publicity; Photographs; Print Pieces, Prints and Engraved Blocks; and Paintings. Files within the subseries are organized alphabetically except for Writings and Publicity which is arranged in chronological order within three sections: Writings by the Artist; Writings About the Artist; and Exhibition Catalogues and Reviews.
  - CORRESPONDENCE
    - Amsterdam Museum, 1905 (Box 210, Folder 2763)
    - Boyd, Rutherford, 1931 May 18 (Box 210, Folder 2764)
    - Brown, John N., 1928 Oct 2 (Box 210, Folder 2765)
    - Dunn, Harvey, 1918 Sept 3 (Box 210, Folder 2766)
    - Hubbell, John Lorenzo, 1927, 1930 (Box 210, Folder 2767)
    - McCormick, Frederick, 1897, 1915 (Box 210, Folder 2768)
    - McCormick, Josephine Newell, 1916-41, n.d. (Box 210, Folder 2769)
    - McCormick, Peter McCormick, Sally, 1916, n.d. (Box 210, Folder 2770)
    - Meier, Nellie Simmons, 1898-1935 (Box 210, Folder 2771)
      See also: Series I, Box 11, Folder 224
    - Newell, Peter, 1910 Dec 26 (Box 210, Folder 2772)
    - Unidentified correspondents, 1922, 1927 (Box 210, Folder 2773)
  - PERSONAL PAPERS
    - McCormick, Sarah E. obituary and interment ticket, 1897 (Box 210, Folder 2774)
    - Men's Neighborhood Club of Leonia keepsake menu, n.d. (Box 210, Folder 2775)
    - National Academy of Design catalogue, 1930 (Box 210, Folder 2776)
    - Taos and New Mexico tourism booklets, ca. 1922 (Box 210, Folder 2777)
  - WRITINGS AND PUBLICITY
    - Writings by Howard McCormick
      - "The Artist's Southwest," in The American Museum Journal, 1913 Mar (Box 210, Folder 2778)
      - "Through the Navajo Region," in Natural History, 1924 (Box 210, Folder 2779)
      - "How I Took Up Wood Engraving," in The Mentor, 1928 Jan (Box 210, Folder 2780)
    - Writings and clippings about Howard McCormick
      - Biographical sketches, unknown Indiana newspapers (Box 210, Folder 2781)
      - Corot painting purchase, n.d. (Box 210, Folder 2782)
      - Miscellaneous, ca. 1900-20 (Box 210, Folder 2783)
      - Indiana visits, 1908, 1921 (Box 210, Folder 2784)
      - "Indiana Illustrators to the Front," in The Indianapolis Sunday Star, 1908 May 17
        See: Oversize, Box 253, Folder 3442
      - "Notable Examples of Wood Engraving," in Printers' Ink, ca. 1909 (Box 210, Folder 2785)
      - "Indiana Artists in the East," in The Indianapolis Sunday Star, 1911 Mar 5
        See: Oversize, Box 253, Folder 3443
      - History of dance fete, New York, 1914 Apr (Box 210, Folder 2786)
      - Lecture, American Museum of Natural History, New York, ca. 1915 (Box 210, Folder 2787)
      - "Artists to Show Works in Leonia Exhibition" in The Bergen Evening Record, 1936 Apr 11
        See: Oversize, Box 253, Folder 3444
      - "Leonia Revives Art Life, Recalls Its Past Glories" in The Bergen Evening Record, 1937 Aug 13 (Box 210, Folder 2788)
      - Leonia Grammar School murals, 1937 Oct (Box 210, Folder 2789)
    - Exhibition catalogues and reviews
      - American Museum of Natural History, New York, Hopi group, 1915 (Box 210, Folder 2790)
      - Painter-Gravers of America, New York, 1917 Apr 1 (Box 210, Folder 2791)
      - American Museum of Natural History, New York, Apache group, 1917 May 18 (Box 210, Folder 2792)
      - John Herron Art Institute, Indianapolis, Indiana, artists, 1918 Mar 30 (Box 210, Folder 2793)
      - American Museum of Natural History, New York, Navajo group, 1924-25 (Box 210, Folder 2794)
      - New Jersey State Museum, Trenton, Jersey, Indians group, ca. 1930 (Box 210, Folder 2795)
      - Winston Dibble Gallery, Englewood, NJ, one-man show, ca. 1930 (Box 210, Folder 2796)
      - Museum of Science and Industry, New York, mural paintings, 1932 (Box 210, Folder 2797)
      - Indiana Society of Print Makers, Indianapolis, members' exhibition, 1936 May (Box 210, Folder 2798)
      - Rochester Public Library, Rochester, MN, one-man show, 1940 Nov (Box 210, Folder 2799)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS
    - Indiana, ca. 1931, n.d. (Box 210, Folder 2800)
    - McCormick, Howard, ca. 1910-35 (Box 210, Folder 2801)
    - Paintings, ca. 1915-35 (Box 210, Folder 2802)
    - Prints and engravings (Box 210, Folder 2803)
    - Red Cross models, 1920 (Box 210, Folder 2804)
    - Southwestern United States
      - Animals and buildings, ca. 1910 (Box 210, Folder 2805)
      - Indians, ca. 1910 (Box 210, Folder 2806)
      - Landscapes, ca. 1910 (Box 210, Folder 2807)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, ca. 1890-1920 (Box 210, Folder 2808)
  - PRINT PIECES, PRINTS AND ENGRAVED BLOCKS
    - Print pieces and tearsheets
      - The Century Magazine
        - "Mexico: A Series of Pictures", 1909 Jul (Box 210, Folder 2809)
          See also: Box 254, Folders 3453-3455
      - Collier's
        - "Dramatic Number" cover, 1908 Oct 24
          See: Oversize, Box 253, Folder 3445
        - "Summer" cover, 1910 Aug 27
          See: Oversize, Box 253, Folder 3446
        - Lincoln portrait for advertisement, 1956
          See: Oversize, Box 253, Folder 3447
      - Gordon, Marcus A., bookplate, n.d. (Box 210, Folder 2810)
      - Indianapolis Music Festival, program cover, 1898 (Box 210, Folder 2811)
      - Indianapolis News illustrations, 1897, n.d. (Box 210, Folder 2812)
      - McCormick family Christmas cards, 1912, 1938, n.d. (Box 210, Folder 2813)
      - The Mentor covers, 1927-29 (Box 210, Folder 2814)
      - Metropolitan "Brittany Peasant Woman," from "The Village Gardens of Brittany" by Katherine Ferris, 1903 Oct (Box 210, Folder 2815)
      - Wertheim, Maurice, bookplate (?), n.d. (Box 210, Folder 2816)
      - Woman's Home Companion illustrations, ca. 1930
        See: Oversize, Box 253, Folder 3448
      - Unidentified publication
        - "A Song of Thanksgiving", 1904 (Box 210, Folder 2817)
      - Unknown clients
        - Anniversary card, 1902 (Box 210, Folder 2818)
        - Political portraits, n.d. (Box 210, Folder 2819)
    - Prints
      See: Oversize Boxes 253 and 254 for the following material:
      - [Fashionable couple, strolling] wood engraving, n.d.
      - [Fashionable couple, seated] wood engraving, after a painting by Dean Cornwell, n.d.
      - [Indian man] wood engraving, 1934
      - [Indian woman] woodcut
      - "Mexico: A Series of Pictures," published in The Century Magazine wood engravings [Title page], 1909
        - "The Toreador", 1909
        - "The Tortilla-Vender", 1909
          See also: Box 210, Folder 2809
      - Mexican subjects wood engravings
        - [Bullfight], n.d.
        - [Filling water jugs at a well], n.d.
        - [Group under an umbrella]
        - [Hay wagon], n.d.
        - [Serenade], n.d.
      - [Old man with jug, hat and cane, portrait of, or after, Harry Townsend] wood engraving
      - [Pianist] wood engraving, n.d.
      - [Southwest scene] wood engraving, n.d.
    - Engraved printing blocks
      - [Filling water jugs at a well] wood, 2-1/2 x 4-1/2 in., n.d. (Box 211, Folder 2820)
      - [Hay wagon] wood, 2-1/2 x 4-1/2 in., n.d. (Box 211, Folder 2821)
      - [Man at well with burro] wood, 6-1/4 x 5-3/4 in., n.d. (Box 211, Folder 2822)
      - [Mask] electrotype, 1-1/8 x 1-1/8 in., n.d. (Box 211, Folder 2823)
      - [Mask] electrotype, 5/8 x 5/8 in., n.d. (Box 211, Folder 2824)
      - [Six figures in a cluster, with house and trees in background] wood, 5-3/4 x 5-1/4 in. (Box 211, Folder 2825)
      - [Worshippers?] wood, 5-1/4 x 5-1/4 in., n.d. (Box 211, Folder 2826)
      - [Undetermined subject, partial plate] copper over lead plate 5-1/2 x 5-3/4 in. (irreg.) (Box 211, Folder 2827)
  - PAINTINGS
    - The Coming of Ahul (Hopi Katchina) gesso on board, 29 x 30-3/4 in.; in carved and painted wood frame (Box art, Folder 2828)
    - Evening (Hopi Buttes, 1st Mesa, Polacoa, Arizona) oil on board, 8-1/4 x 10/1/4 in.; has Salmagundi Club Thumb-Box exhibition label on verso
      See: Oversize Box 255
    - Hopi Maiden gesso on board, 13-3/4 x 10/3/4 in.; framed and in fragile condition, 1940
    - Hopi Man gouache on paper, 10 x 8 in., 1908
    - [Three gazelles] gesso on board, 16-3/4 x 17 in.; framed, 1938 (Box art, Folder 2829)
- Alfred Zantzinger Baker Jr. Papers, 1892-1986; Series VIII; 5.5; (13 boxes)
  Series VIII holds two subseries: Baker's Peter Newell Biography Project files, and his Personal Correspondence and Papers.
  - PETER NEWELL BIOGRAPHY PROJECT
    This subseries of Baker's papers includes administrative and subject files covering his research on Peter Newell and the placement of the Peter Newell Family Papers. The papers are organized as: Administrative Files; Biographical Writings; and Research Files. Research Files are further subdivided by: Authors and Publishers; Corporate Clients; Family Members; Locales (with people and institutions thereunder), and Miscellaneous. Dates given reflect the original material in the files and not the dates of material that Baker had photocopied for his research.
    - Administrative Files
      - Charles E. Tuttle Co., Inc., 1970-71 (Box 212, Folder 2830)
      - Newell Manufacturing Company, 1930 (Box 212, Folder 2831)
      - Newell papers placement, 1932-73 (Box 212, Folder 2832)
      - Newell papers storage, 1964, 1970 (Box 212, Folder 2833)
      - Reader cards, 1948-74 (Box 212, Folder 2834)
      - Receipts and expenses, 1935-80 (Box 212, Folder 2835)
      - Yale University
        - Clippings, 1957-82 (Box 212, Folder 2836)
        - Correspondence, 1964-86 (Box 212, Folder 2837)
        - Inventories and notes (Box 212, Folder 2838)
        - Duplicate inventories, n.d. (Box 212, Folder 2839)
    - Biographical Writings
      - "And Time is Fleeting" corrected typescript (Box 212, Folder 2840)
      - "Peter Newell Outline [1880-94]" typescript with corrections and additions (Box 212, Folder 2841)
      - "PN Outline" (version of above) corrected typescript, n.d. (Box 212, Folder 2842)
      - "Random and uncorrected notes" corrected typescripts and manuscripts, 1978, n.d. (Box 212, Folder 2843)
      - Random draft pages, corrected typescripts (Box 212, Folder 2844)
      - "The Tree's Inclined" (chapter title, two versions) corrected typescripts, n.d. (Box 212, Folder 2845)
      - Untitled draft corrected typescript, n.d. (Box 212, Folder 2846)
    - Research Files - Authors and Publishers
      - Bangs, John Kendrick, 1941-68, n.d. (Box 212, Folder 2847)
      - Bates, Frances, 1945-47, n.d. (Box 212, Folder 2848)
      - Brooks, Hildegard, n.d. (Box 212, Folder 2849)
      - Burgess, Gelett, 1941-51, n.d. (Box 212, Folder 2850)
      - Burns, Lee, 1944 (Box 212, Folder 2851)
      - Cobb, Irvin S., 1912-59 (Box 212, Folder 2852)
      - Crane, Stephen, 1937-85, n.d. (Box 212, Folder 2853)
      - Curtiss, Philip, 1943, 1964 (Box 212, Folder 2854)
      - Egan, Maurice Francis, 1924 (Box 212, Folder 2855)
      - Garnett, Louise Ayres, 1944-46 (Box 212, Folder 2856)
      - Harper and Brothers, 1906-58, n.d. (Box 212, Folder 2857)
      - Hearn, Michael Patrick, 1985 (Box 212, Folder 2858)
      - Hill, Carolyn Bailey, 1943, 1961 (Box 212, Folder 2859)
      - Holt, Henry and Company, 1944-52 (Box 212, Folder 2860)
      - Houghton, Carolyn
        See: Carolyn Houghton Wells, Box 213, folder 2870
      - Hughes, Rupert, 1946, 1956 (Box 212, Folder 2861)
      - Irwin, Wallace, 1943-59 (Box 213, Folder 2862)
      - Johnson, Burges, 1921-63 (Box 213, Folder 2863)
      - Lee, Albert, 1946-58 (Box 213, Folder 2864)
      - Loomis, Charles Battell, 1908-68, n.d. (Box 213, Folder 2865)
      - Reed, Myrtle, 1944, n.d. (Box 213, Folder 2866)
      - Stone, Stuart B., 1944 (Box 213, Folder 2867)
      - Towne, Charles Hanson, 1943-49 (Box 213, Folder 2868)
      - Twain, Mark, 1970-85 (Box 213, Folder 2869)
      - Wells, Carolyn Houghton, 1937, 1939 (Box 213, Folder 2870)
      - Wheelock, Matilda Henderson, 1945, 1958 (Box 213, Folder 2871)
      - Woollcott, Alexander, 1931, 1937 (Box 213, Folder 2872)
      - The Youth's Companion, 1955 (Box 213, Folder 2873)
      - Obituaries and biographies of authors, editors and publishers, 1939-78 (Box 213, Folder 2874)
    - Research Files - Corporate Clients
      - Illinois Agricultural Works, 1944-84 (Box 213, Folder 2875)
      - Illinois College, Jacksonville, 1946-81 (Box 213, Folder 2876)
      - Murphy Varnish Company, 1944 (Box 213, Folder 2877)
      - Pacific Coast Borax Company, 1913-77 (Box 213, Folder 2878)
      - Rogers Peet Company, 1953-54 (Box 213, Folder 2879)
      - Victor Talking Machine Company, 1975 (Box 213, Folder 2880)
    - Research Files - Family Members
      - Ashcraft family, 1955-78, n.d. (Box 214, Folder 2881)
      - Baker, Alfred Z., Sr., family, 1979, n.d. (Box 214, Folder 2882)
      - Baker, Eva Graff, 1921, n.d. (Box 214, Folder 2883)
      - Baker family tree, n.d. (Box 214, Folder 2884)
      - Cooke, Claudine Nankivel, 1966-77 (Box 214, Folder 2885)
      - Cooke, Claudine Nankivel, 1978-80, n.d. (Box 214, Folder 2886)
      - Cosgrove, Betty (Helen) Baker, 1980 (Box 214, Folder 2887)
      - Gordon family, 1964-76, n.d. (Box 214, Folder 2888)
      - Gordon, Marcus and Helen Newell, 1969, 1971 (Box 214, Folder 2889)
      - Gordon, Robert (Stubby) Bruce, 1948, 1970 (Box 214, Folder 2890)
      - Hooper family, 1958-62, n.d. (Box 214, Folder 2891)
      - Lydecker, Sally McCormick and Garrit, 1960-81, n.d. (Box 214, Folder 2892)
      - McCormick, Frederick, 1929-63 (Box 214, Folder 2893)
      - McCormick, Howard
        - Correspondence and notes, 1941, n.d. (Box 214, Folder 2894)